Daniel Carter Beard Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, circa 1865-1941 (Box 19-147)
  - Engler, Henry R.
  - Evans, S. Keith
  - Evans Curio Store (Box 46)
  - Everitt, Charles P.
  - Explorers Club
  - "E-Ely" miscellaneous
  - "Ema-Ey" miscellaneous (Box 47)
  - Fager, Volta (Box 48)
  - Fairchild, George Winfield
  - Farley, James A.
  - Faucett, Henry M.
  - Fazzini, Lillian
  - Fechheimer Bros. Co.
  - Feyl, Harold V.
  - Fiala, Anthony
  - Field, Marshall
  - Field and Stream
  - Finkelstein, Lillian
  - Finley, John H.
  - Finn, Jonathan
  - Fisher, E. A.
  - Fisher, George J.
  - Fisher, George J. (Box 49)
  - Fisher, Mitchell S.
  - Fisher, William A.
  - Fisher Body Craftsman's Guild
  - Fitch, Ezra
  - Fitch, James P. (Box 50)
  - Fitch, Joseph
  - Fleming, Henry S.
  - Fleming, Joseph S.
  - Flemming, Arthur S.
  - Flushing Peace Society
  - Folger, B. W.
  - Forbus, Arthur R.
  - Force, C. W.
  - Ford, Henry
  - Forest Lake Club
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson
  - Fowler, Kenneth
  - Fox, Charles Edwin
  - Fox, J. Chester
  - Frank, Glenn
  - Frazer, John F. See Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Frederick, Karl T.
  - Freeman, Judson P.
  - Freeman, Martin B.
  - Freeman, Martin B. (Box 51)
  - French, George W.
  - Fretwell, Elbert
  - Friends of Children, Inc.
  - The Frontier
  - Frost, William Goodell
  - Frothingham, Robert
  - Fuertes, Louis Robert
  - Fuller, G.
  - "Fag-Fal" miscellaneous
  - "Fam-Fur" miscellaneous (Box 52-53)
  - Gammons, Charles A. (Box 54)
  - Gannon, John E.
  - Gardner, Raymond E.
  - Garfield, James R.
  - Garland, Hamlin
  - Garner, John Nance
  - Gary, Rex I.
  - Gaskin, J. A.
  - Gates, Don S.
  - Gawtry, Lewis
  - Gearhart, E. M.
  - Gendall, Gilbert H.
  - General Feather Trading Co.
  - George, Henry
  - George, Henry, Jr.
  - Gibbons, Floyd
  - Gibson, Charles Dana
  - Gibson, Mrs. Charles Dana
  - Gibson, Langdon (Box 55)
  - Gignilliat, L. R. See Container 37, Culver Military Academy
  - Gilbert, Alfred C.
  - Gilder, Robert W.
  - Gilder, Rodman
  - Gill, Emlyn M.
  - Gipsy Trail Camp
  - Gles, J. S.
  - Glynn, Martin
  - Good Housekeeping
  - Goodhue, Bertram Grosvenor
  - Goodman, R. G.
  - Gordon, Harvey A.
  - Gosden, Freeman
  - Gratz, Homer
  - Graves, Henry S.
  - Gray, Frank
  - Grayson, Cary T.
  - Greeley, William B. See Container 33, Camp-Fire Club (Box 56)
  - Green, Carl R.
  - Green, Forrest
  - Green, George E.
  - Greenhawk, Frank A.
  - Gregor, Elmer R.
  - Grey, Lina Elise
  - Grey, Zane
  - Grier, Walter L.
  - Griffith, Ernest S.
  - Grinnell, George Bird
  - Griswold, Lester
  - Grolier Society
  - Grosset & Dunlap
  - Grosvenor, Gilbert
  - Guards of Washington
  - Guest, Edgar A.
  - Guggenheimer, Milton C.
  - Guiterman, Arthur
  - Guiterman, Leo
  - Gulick, Donald
  - "G-Garr" miscellaneous
  - "Gart-Gw" miscellaneous (Box 57-58)
  - Haddock, Arthur H. (Box 59)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann
  - Hall, Bolton
  - Hammond, John Hays
  - Harlan, Esther
  - Harper, Horatio
  - Harper & Brothers
  - Hart, William S.
  - Haskell, William S.
  - Hastings, George T.
  - Hays, Will H.
  - Head, Walter W.
  - Head, Walter W. (Box 60)
  - Heath, Albert G.
  - Heath (D.C.) & Co.
  - Heatter, Gabriel (Box 61)
  - Heistand, Charles M.
  - Hemingray, Ralph
  - Henry George School of Social Science
  - Hession, John W.
  - Heye, George G. See Container 20, American Indian
  - Hitchcock, Frederick H.
  - Hodgson, Casper
  - Hoisington, Fred See Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Holcombe, Alexander
  - Holcombe, Willis B.
  - Holland, Leicester B. See also Container 75, Library of Congress
  - Hoover, Herbert
  - Hoover, J. Edgar
  - Hornaday, William T.
  - Hornbeck, Louis A.
  - Houghton, Augustus S. (Box 62)
  - Houston, Herbert S.
  - Howard, Clarence
  - Howard, Roy W.
  - Howells, William Dean
  - Hubbard, A. G.
  - Hubbard, William S.
  - Hubbell, George L.
  - Hughes, Allene G.
  - Hughes, Charles Evans
  - Hughes, Howard
  - Hughes, Howard R.
  - Hulse, Mina M. Edison
  - Hungerford, Herbert
  - Hurt, Huber William
  - Hutchins, Robert M.
  - "H-Hy" miscellaneous (Box 63-67)
  - Ickes, Harold L.
  - Illustrators, Society of
  - Indian Association of America
  - Invitations
  - Ivory, Lindsay C.
  - "Id-Iz" miscellaneous
  - J. B. Lippincott Company
    - 1911-1924
    - 1925-1939
  - Jefferson, Joseph See Container 51, Fuller, G.
  - Jelliffe, W. R. See Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Johnson, Bruce
  - Johnson, James W.
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood
  - Jones, Howard Mumford
  - Joseph, Nannine
  - J-Johnson, L.
  - Johnson, M.-Ju
  - Keane, Thomas J.
  - Keller, Helen
  - Kelly, Luther S.
  - Kent, H. W.
  - Kerr, John C.
  - Kettering, Charles F.
  - Kight, H. O.
  - Kindig, Joe
  - Klinck, Jacob C.
  - Knickerbocker, William S.
  - Knight, Harry C.
  - Knox, Taber
  - Krishna menon, V. K.
  - Kunitz, Stanley J.
  - Kyle, Paul
  - "K-Ky" miscellaneous (Box 73-74)
  - Ladies Home Journal (Box 75)
  - Laffoon, Ruby
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello H.
  - Lamb, Charles R.
  - Lamb, Peter O.
  - Lane, Franklin K.
  - Lasky, Jesse L.
  - Lawes, Lewis E.
  - Lawrence, D. W.
  - Lawrence, Robert
  - Lawrence, Townsend
  - Lawyer, George A.
  - Leach, Henry Goddard
  - League of Nations
  - Lee, Jack
  - Leggett, Thomas H.
  - Lehman, Eugene H.
  - Lehman, Herbert H.
  - Le Master, B. W.
  - LeMessurier, Albert M.
  - Library of Congress See also Container 61, Holland, Leicester
  - Lindbergh, Charles A.
  - Lindsay, Benjamin
  - Lippincott, J. B. (Box 76)
  - Lippincott, Joseph W.
  - Littlejohn, C. H.
  - Livingston, Colin H.
  - Loeb, William
  - Lombardi, Remo M.
  - Longworth, Nicholas
  - Looker, Earle
  - Loomis, Edward E.
  - Loomis, Ormond E.
  - Loughran, Robert L.
  - Lounsberry, Harry
  - Lovett, Fremont L.
  - Low, Raymond F.
  - Lowerre, M. V.
  - "L-Ly" miscellaneous (Box 77-78)
  - McAdoo, W. G. (Box 79)
  - McAdoo, Mrs. W. G.
  - McDonald, L. L.
  - McEwen, John D.
  - McGuire, Walter P.
  - Mack, Connie
  - McKelway, St. Clair
  - McLean, Marshall
  - McLean, Marshall (Box 80)
  - McLean, W. A. See Container 49, Fisher Body Craftsman's Guild
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - Macmillan, William
  - McNally, Fred L.
  - MacNeil, Herman A.
  - McVey, Frank
  - Manhattan Single Tax Club
  - Mark Twain Memorial Foundation
  - Markham, Edwin
  - Markham, Virgil
  - Martin, Edward Sanford (Box 81-84)
  - Marquis (A. N.) Co. (Box 85)
  - Martin, Hubert
  - Martin-New York Tent and Duck Co.
  - Masson, Thomas L.
  - Mathiews, Franklin K. See also Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Mathiews, Norman T. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Medalists, Society of
  - Mellon, Andrew W.
  - Mencken, H. L.
  - Menninger, Karl
  - Menninger, William C.
  - Merriam, C. Hart
  - Merrill, Haydon O.
  - Metzger, Sol
  - Millar, J. H.
  - Miller, A. J.
  - Miller, Joaquin
  - Miller, Warren H. See Container 48, Field and Stream
  - Millikan, Robert A.
  - Mills, Fred C.
  - Mitchel, John P.
  - Mitchell, J. A.
  - Mitchell, J. van Beuren
  - Möller, J. A. L. See Container 33, Camp-Fire Club (Box 86)
  - Moffat, Samuel A.
  - Moffat, W. D.
  - Moffat, Yard & Co.
  - Monahan, Mike
  - Mook, Delo E.
  - Mooney, James E.
  - Moore, John Bassett
  - Morris, Ernest J.
  - Morris, Robert T.
  - Morse, Frank T.
  - Morse, Perley
  - Muir, John
  - Murray, William D.
  - "M-My" miscellaneous (Box 87-91)
  - National Board of Review (Box 92)
  - National Geographic Magazine
  - National Motion Picture League
  - National Nut Tree Planting Project
  - Neill, Wallace L.
  - Ness, Eliot
  - New York Public Library
  - New York Military Academy See also Container 41, David, Milton
  - New York Times
  - New York Zoological Society
  - Nichols, Mary A.
  - Nicol, James W.
  - North, Sterling (Box 93)
  - Northrup, Carl F.
  - "N-New" miscellaneous
  - "New-Ny" miscellaneous (Box 94)
  - Oakley, George W.
  - Ochs, Adolph S.
  - O'Connor, Evelyn See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Ogden, Rollo
  - Olmsted, George C.
  - Olson, A. C.
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield (Box 95)
  - Oursler, Fulton
  - Outdoor Recreation, National Conference on
  - The Outing
  - The Outlook
  - "O-Oz" miscellaneous
  - Page, Walter Hines (Box 96)
  - Paine, Albert Bigelow
  - Paris, Mrs. John W.
  - Parker, Grace
  - Parsons, John E.
  - Parsons, Reginald
  - Partridge, Jesse D.
  - Pathé Exchange
  - Patrick, Luther
  - Patterson, Henry S.
  - Patten, F. J. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Patton, J. Woodbridge
  - Paul, G. Hurst
  - Penfield, Edward
  - Perelson, A. E.
  - Perkins, Maxwell
  - Perry, Armstrong
  - Perry, William A.
  - Pershing, John J.
  - Phelps, William Lyon
  - Philadephia Sesquicentennial International Exposition
  - Phillips, Frank
  - Phillips, John M.
  - Philo, Ralph M.
  - Pi Gamma Mu (Box 97)
  - Pictorial Review See also Container 121, Vance, Arthur
  - Pinchot, Gifford
  - Pine, Charles
  - Pitz, Henry C.
  - The Players
  - Plessis, Albert L.
  - Plimpton, George L.
  - Poey, Joseph (Box 98)
  - Poling, Daniel A.
  - Pollock, Channing
  - Popular Mechanics
  - Popular Science Monthly
  - Porter, George D.
  - Porter, Helen Talbot
  - Post, Augustus
  - Post, Louis F.
  - Powlison, Ernest K.
  - Pratt, George Dupont
  - Pratt, George Dupont See also Container 33, Camp-Fire Club (Box 99)
  - Pratt, Horace C.
  - Presbrey, Charles
  - Presbrey, Frank
  - Presbrey, Frank (Box 100)
  - Prettyman, Ida Presley
  - Prevatil, James
  - Price, Robroy
  - Proctor, Arthur W.
  - Pulsifer, William E.
  - Putnam, George Palmer
  - Putnam, Herbert
  - Putnam, J. B.
  - Putnam's (G. P.) Sons
  - "P-Pay" miscellaneous
  - "Pea-Py" miscellaneous (Box 101-102)
  - Queens Council Camp Committee (Box 103)
  - Queens County Savings Bank
  - Quetico-, Superior Council
  - "Qua-Qui" miscellaneous
  - Ransdell, Mrs. Joseph E.
  - Rasmussen, D.
  - Rathgeber, Emile E.
  - Reader's Digest
  - Recreation
  - Redbook
  - Reed, Robert See Container 36, Country Gentleman
  - Remington, Frederic
  - Rhead, Louis
  - Rice, Arthur F. See also Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Rice, Charles E.
  - Rice, Ralston
  - Rice, Sidney L.
  - Rich, G. Barrett (Box 104)
  - Rich, George H.
  - Rich, J. Hampton
  - Ridgway, Roy D.
  - Rigney, Francis J.
  - Rinehart, Stanley M.
  - Ripley, George S.
  - Ripley, Robert L.
  - Risley, George E.
  - Robert Schalkenbach Foundation
  - Roberts, Arthur E.
  - Robinson, Frank N.
  - Rockefeller, John D.
  - Rockland Light and Power Co.
  - Rockwell, Norman
  - Rogers, George T.
  - Rogers, Mary Cochrane
  - Rogers, Will
  - Rogers Peet Co.
  - Roosevelt, Archie
  - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit Carow
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (Box 105)
  - Roosevelt, Grace Green
  - Roosevelt, Kermit
  - Roosevelt, Theodore
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr.
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, III
  - Roosevelt Memorial Association
  - Roosevelt Memorial Association, Woman's
  - Root, Elihu (Box 106)
  - Root, Joseph E.
  - Roselius, Ludwig
  - Rosenbach, A. S. W.
  - Rosenzweig, Jacob
  - Rosenzweig, Jack
  - Ross, Lanny
  - Rotary Club
  - Rowe, L. S.
  - Royal Arcanum (Flushing Council)
  - Russell, C. M.
  - Russell, Walter
  - "R-Rey" miscellaneous
  - "Rh-Ruc" miscellaneous (Box 107)
  - "Rud-Ry" miscellaneous (Box 108)
  - Sackett, Milton B.
  - Saint Nicholas
  - Saltiel, William David
  - Sampson, Fleming D.
  - Sampson, Lewis D. (Box 109)
  - Sanborn, D. A.
  - Sanborn, Edwin W.
  - Sanford, Clay
  - Sanford, Daniel S.
  - Saunders, DeWitt
  - Saunders, Dorothy
  - Saunders, W. Lawrence
  - Sawtelle, Alvin C.
  - Sayre, Joel
  - Schiff, John M.
  - Schiff, Mortimer
  - Schuck, Arthur A.
  - Schuler, Loring See Container 36, Country Gentlemen
  - Schutt, Peter
  - Schwab, Charles M.
  - Schuyler, Remington
  - Scribner, Arthur H.
  - Scribner, Charles (Box 110)
  - Seaman, Frank
  - Seton, Ernest Thompson
  - Sewell, Walter
  - Seymour, Edmund See also Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Seymour, Julius
  - Seymour, Roy F.
  - Seymour, Walter B.
  - Seymour, William W.
  - Sharpe, O. D. (Box 111)
  - Shaw, Albert
  - Sherburne, Joe
  - Shields, Amos R.
  - S'hiuhushu, Barnabas
  - Shriner, Clarence E.
  - Sibley, Carroll
  - Sigmund, Eisner
  - Sikes, George R.
  - Simpson, Benjamin L.
  - Sinclair, H. W.
  - Sinclair, Upton
  - Skier, A. M.
  - Skier (A. M.) Agency
  - Smeltzer, Robert E.
  - Smith, Alfred E.
  - Smith, Benjamin A.
  - Smith, Bolton
  - Smith, George Albert
  - Smith, J. F.
  - Smith, Kate
  - Smith, William H.
  - Smith, William Lord
  - Smith, William Parker
  - Smithsonian Institution
  - Sniffen, Robert P.
  - Society of Friends
  - Soules, William B. (Box 112)
  - Southern New England Telephone Co.
  - Southworth, Irving F.
  - Sparrow, Thomas
  - Spence, Bernard L. See also Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Spencer, Lorrilard
  - Spiegle, Frederick M.
  - Spivak, Lawrence
  - Spivey, A. G.
  - Stahlnecker, P. S.
  - Stayton, B. W.
  - Stearns, Myron M. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Steele, Frederic Dorr
  - Stefansson, Wilhjalmer
  - Stern, Alfred Whital
  - Stetson, Sereno
  - Stiles, John A.
  - Stockwell, John Wesley
  - Stokes, John A.
  - Stone, Andrew J.
  - Stone, Ezra
  - Stone, William M.
  - Storrow, James J.
  - Stoutenburgh, Abram S.
  - Stoutenburgh, Sara
  - Straight, Willard
  - Stratton, Leslie
  - Suffern National Bank (Box 113)
  - Sutton, Isaac
  - Swan, Joseph
  - Syms, Parker See also Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - "S-Sai" miscellaneous
  - "Sak-Stri" miscellaneous (Box 114-117)
  - "Stro-Sz" miscellaneous (Box 118)
  - Taft, Helen H.
  - Taft, Lorado
  - Taft, William H.
  - Tarbell, Ida
  - Tatham, Charles
  - Taylor, Albert S.
  - Thomas, Lowell
  - Thomassen, Henry S.
  - Tisch, Julius
  - Tompkins, William
  - Towers, Walter K. See Container 20, American Boy
  - Town Hall Club
  - Toy, Charles
  - Trees, Clyde C.
  - Tressler, Charles C.
  - Trexler, Albert E.
  - Trotta, Lamar
  - Trumbull, John H.
  - Tucker, John F.
  - Twilight Club
  - "T-Ty" miscellaneous (Box 119-120)
  - Underwood and Underwood (Box 121)
  - Unger, Peter J.
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture
  - U.S. Department of the Interior
  - University Club
  - Upton, Louis
  - "Uh-Ut" miscellaneous
  - Vance, Arthur See also Container 97, Pictorial Review and Container 138, Woman's Home Companion
  - Van Doren, Irita
  - Van Dyke, Henry
  - Van Inwegen, Ethel
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem (Box 122)
  - Van Norden, Ottomar H.
  - Victory Hall Association
  - Vilas, Royal L.
  - Vitalius, E. H.
  - Vitalius, E. H. (Box 123-124)
  - Vitalius, E. H. (Box 125)
  - Vreeland, Frederick K.
  - Vreeland, Frederick K. (Box 126)
  - "Vag-Vie" miscellaneous
  - "Vig-Vu" miscellaneous (Box 127)
  - Wack, Henry Wellington
  - Wadsworth, James A.
  - Walcott, W. C.
  - Wallace, DeWitt
  - Wallace, Dillon
  - Wallace, John
  - Wallace, Lew
  - Wallschlaeger, F. O.
  - Walters, Sara
  - Wanamaker, Rodman
  - Ward, John Quincy Adams
  - Waring, Fred
  - Warner, John D.
  - Washington, Booker T.
  - Washington, E. Davidson
  - Watling, John W.
  - Watres, Louis A.
  - Watson, Thomas J.
  - Watson, William H.
  - Weaver, Charles
  - Webb, Charles H.
  - Webster, Charles
  - Webster, Fred
  - Webster, H. T.
  - Weeks, John W.
  - Weiler, Jack
  - Weir, John E.
  - Welch, William A.
  - Wells, Clarence R.
  - Wenner, Richard
  - Wertheim, Edward L.
  - Wessell, William C.
  - West, James E. (Box 128-137)
  - Westhoff, Gisela (Box 138)
  - Whalen, Grover
  - Wheat, R. M.
  - Wheeler, Burton K.
  - White, William Allen
  - Whitney, Caspar
  - Whitson, Abraham U.
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman
  - Williams, Allen S.
  - Willison, J. C.
  - Willson, Paul W. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Wilson, Charles N.
  - Wilson, Margaret Woodrow
  - Wilson, Thomas E.
  - Wilson, Woodrow
  - Windsor, Edward Duke of
  - Winninger, Charles
  - Wintress, James E.
  - Wise, Steven S.
  - Wister, Owen
  - Woman's Home Companion See also Container 121, Vance, Arthur
  - Wood, Charles E.
  - Wood, John W.
  - Wood, Leonard
  - Woodard, Adele F. See Container 92, National Motion Picture League
  - Woodruff, Jack B.
  - Woolf, S. J.
  - Worden, C. A.
  - Worden, C. A. (Box 139)
  - Wozencraft, Frank W.
  - Wright, Frank W.
  - Wright, Herman E.
  - Wright, Orville
  - Wyeth, N. C.
  - Wyland, Ray O.
  - Wynn, Ed
  - "W-Was" miscellaneous
  - "Wate-Worr" miscellaneous (Box 140-142)
  - "Wort-Wyo" miscellaneous (Box 143)
  - Young, Owen D.
  - The Youth's Companion
  - "Ya-Yu" miscellaneous
  - Zaner, Ray F.
  - "Z" miscellaneous and unidentified
  - Greeting cards (Box 144-146)
  - Greeting cards (Box 147)
  - Greeting card list
  - Collected autograph letters
  - Letters sent and received from persons other than Beard
- Special Correspondence, 1915-1940 (Box 148-208)
  Correspondence relating to the Dan Beard Outdoor School for Boys, the Boy Scouts, and Sons of Daniel Boone.
  Dan Beard Outdoor School for Boys letters are arranged by year from 1915 through 1940, with the letters from 1915 through 1924 arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. Letters relating to the Boy Scouts and Sons of Daniel Boone are unarranged.
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 148-150)
  - Dan Beard Outdoor School for Boys (Box 151)
    - 1915
    - 1916-1919
      - "A-B" miscellaneous
      - "B" miscellaneous (Box 152)
      - "B-C" miscellaneous (Box 153)
      - "C-F" miscellaneous (Box 154)
      - "F-G" miscellaneous (Box 155)
      - "G-J" miscellaneous (Box 156)
      - "J-L" miscellaneous (Box 157)
      - "L-M" miscellaneous (Box 158)
      - "M-R" miscellaneous (Box 159)
      - "R" miscellaneous (Box 160)
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Seymour, Edmund (Box 161)
      - Seymour, Julius
      - Seymour, Julius (Box 162)
      - Sutton, Isaac
      - "S" miscellaneous (Box 163)
      - "S-V" miscellaneous (Box 164)
      - "V-Z" miscellaneous (Box 165)
    - 1920-1921 (Box 166)
      - "A-B" miscellaneous
      - "C-G" miscellaneous (Box 167)
      - "H-K" miscellaneous (Box 168)
      - "L-R" miscellaneous (Box 169)
      - Seymour, Edmund (Box 170)
      - "S" miscellaneous
      - "T" miscellaneous (Box 171)
    - 1919-1920, applications for employment
    - 1922-1924 (Box 172)
      - "A-D" miscellaneous
      - "D-G" miscellaneous (Box 173)
      - "G-M" miscellaneous (Box 174)
      - "M-Q" miscellaneous (Box 175)
      - "R-S" miscellaneous (Box 176)
      - "S-Z" miscellaneous (Box 177)
    - 1925
    - 1925 (Box 178)
    - 1925-1926 (Box 179)
    - 1926 (Box 180)
    - 1926 (Box 181)
      - McPheters, Abner
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Sutton, Isaac
      - Board of Directors
      - Camp diaries
    - 1927
      - General
      - General (Box 183-183)
    - 1927 (Box 184)
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Sutton, Isaac
      - President's report
      - Board of Directors
      - Applications for employment
    - 1928
      - General
      - General (Box 185)
      - President's report (Box 186)
      - Board of Directors
    - 1929
      - General
      - General (Box 187)
    - 1929-1930, general (Box 188)
    - 1930 (Box 189)
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Sutton, Isaac
      - Board of Directors
    - 1931
      - General
    - 1931 (Box 190)
    - 1931-1932, general (Box 191)
    - 1932 (Box 192)
      - General
      - Seymour, Edmund (Box 193)
      - Sutton, Isaac
    - 1933
      - General
      - General (Box 194)
      - Rich, George
    - 1934
      - General
      - Rich, George
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Sutton, Isaac (Box 195)
    - 1935
      - General
      - General (Box 196)
      - Rich, George
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Sutton, Isaac
    - 1936
      - General
      - General (Box 197-198)
      - General (Box 199)
      - Rich, George
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Sutton, Isaac (Box 200)
    - 1937
      - General
      - General (Box 201)
      - Rich, George
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Sutton, Isaac
    - 1938
      - General
      - Rich, George (Box 202)
      - Sutton, Isaac
    - 1939
      - General
      - General (Box 203)
      - Rich, George
      - Seymour, Edmund
      - Sutton, Isaac
    - 1940, general
    - Miscellaneous
      - Abercrombie, Robert
      - Loughran, Robert
      - Post, Augustus
      - Board of Directors and stockholders
      - Boy Scouts of America
      - Financial papers (Box 204)
      - Insurance
      - Merit badge awards
      - Merit badge awards (Box 205)
      - President's reports
      - Applications for employment
      - Form letters
      - Advertisements (correspondence)
  - Sons of Daniel Boone (Box 206-208)
- Subject File (Box 209-221)
  Correspondence, writings, reports, lists, minutes, and other papers.
  Arranged by name of subject, organization, or type of material.
  - Boy Pioneers (Box 209)
  - Boy Scouts of America (origin)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 210-211)
  - Printed matter (Box 212)
  - Boys' Life
    - Questions and answers column
    - Questions and answers column (Box 213-215)
    - Questions and answers column (Box 216)
  - Buckskin Men of America
  - Camp Directors Association
  - Camp-Fire Club of America
    - Minutes
  - Camp Fire of America (Box 217)
  - "Dan Beard Rifle" (Dickey air rifle)
  - Dan Beard Outdoor School for Boys
    - Advertisements
    - Advertisements (Box 218)
  - "The Powder Horn"
  - National Court of Honor (Box 219-220)
  - National Court of Honor (Box 221)
  - Sons of Daniel Boone (membership lists)
  - Theodore Roosevelt pilgrimages
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1890-1940 (Box 222-244)
  Speeches, articles, book material, and other writings.
  Arranged by type of writing.
  - Speeches (Box 222)
    - Alphabetical by title, "Cruelty and Brutality"-"Trees and Boys"
    - Chronological
      - 3 Sept. 1890-22 May 1936
      - 24 Oct. 1936-1940 (Box 223)
      - Undated
  - Interview
  - Articles (Box 224)
    - Alphabetical by title
      - "Abraham Lincoln"-"Come, Come, Let Us Be Merry!"
      - "Com-pa-ny At-ten-shun"-"Funeral of Henry George" (Box 225)
      - "Geological Hikes by Request"-"Hawking" (Box 226)
      - "The Heart Must Ring the Christmas Bells"-"How To Make Billy Bow-Leg Moccasins" (Box 227)
      - "How To Make Blue Cloud Buckskin Leggins"-"Life Begins at Eighty" (Box 228)
      - "Lincoln's Boy Scout Month"-"Putting the Sun Back in the Sky" (Box 229)
      - "A Rattling Good Time"-"Surveying" (Box 230)
      - "Swine Herding Time"-"A Young George Washington" (Box 231)
    - Chronological (Box 232)
      - 13 Dec. 1914-Apr. 1937
      - Undated
      - Undated (Box 233)
    - Printed articles
  - Short stories
    - "Four Boats, Two Shoes, and a Foot Store"
    - "Love Conquers Everything"
  - Introduction to Warpath and Cattle Trail
  - Review of Buffalo Days, by Homer W. Wheeler
  - Poems
  - Printed reviews of books by Daniel Carter Beard
  - Books (Box 234)
    - The American Boys' Book of Birds and Brownies of the Woods, preface
    - The American Boys' Handy Book
      - Contents
      - Royalty
      - Statements
    - Bugs, Butterflies and Beetles
      - Introduction
    - Hardly a Man Is Now Alive
      - Typescript
      - Final draft (Box 235-240)
      - Final draft (Box 241)
    - Mystery of the Blue Goose
    - Mystery of the Blue Goose (Box 242)
    - Fragments (Box 243-244)
- Miscellany (Box 245-261)
  Address books, calendars, biographical papers, composition books, financial matter, photographs, printed material, a scrapbook, and other miscellaneous items.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Address books (Box 245)
  - Bills and receipts
  - Biographical papers
  - Biographical papers (Box 246)
  - Composition books (Box 247)
  - Engagement calendars (Box 248-254)
    - 1917-1939
    - 1940 (Box 255)
  - Financial papers
  - Photographs
  - General miscellany (Box 256-259)
  - Printed matter (Box 260)
  - Nature scrapbook See Oversize
- Oversize (Box OV 1-OV 2)
  Printed drawings and a scrapbook.